# CURRICULUM VITAE

## **PERSONAL DETAILS**

NAME : SAMUEL MUNIALO SENENI

NATIONAL ID NO: 29611216 PHONE NO : 0792-529 532

EMAIL : <u>samuelmunialo2005@gmail.com</u>

GENDER : MALE

DATE OF BIRTH: 27<sup>TH</sup> December,1992

NATIONALITY: KENYAN.

#### **PERSONAL SUMMARY**

A bright, talented and ambitious IT PERSON with a KNEC ICT Diploma holder and Cisco Certified Network Associate and I have more four years working experience as ICT TRAINER/ICT TECHNICIAN AND ICT SUPPORT. I have strong ICT background who possesses self-discipline and the ability to work with the minimum of supervision. Having exposure to a wide range of technologies & able to play a key role in diagnosing hardware and software problems, installing and configuring software and hardware, backup of data and to ensure that quality solutions meet business objectives. Possessing a good team spirit, deadline orientated and having the ability to organize and present complex solutions clearly and accurately. Looking for a suitable IT job position with a successful and dynamic company that offers room for progression.

### **CAREER GOALS**

- > To become expert in the area of ICT.
- To advance another level of education.
- > To undertake training development courses and gain qualification of the job.

#### **KEY SKILLS AND COMPETENCIES**

- Configuration, installation and maintenance of computer networks (Router and Switch).
- Knowledge of operating systems, networking, hardware and software.
- > Configuration, maintenance and repair of ICT devices and other peripherals.
- > ICT security; Cybersecurity, anti-virus and firewalls.
- Linux operating system.
- Graphic design.
- Website development (HTML, CSS and JAVASCRIPT).
- Microsoft 365 Azure Cloud.
- Training of computer users/ Support end Users.
- Social media such as Facebook manager, You Tube, Instagram and Twitter
- Records Managements
- Creativity and innovation.
- Excellent communication skills, Organizational skills and Problem-solving skills.

## **EDUCATION BACKGROUND/TECHNICAL QUALIFICATION**

INSTITUTIONS	YEAR OF STUDY	QUILIFICATION
DOMINION TRAINING INSTITUTE	2014 TO 2017	KNEC DIPLOMA IN INFORMATION COMMUNICATION AND TECHNOLOGY (ICT- PASS)
IGARA SECONDARY SCHOOL	2008 TO 2011	KENYA CERTIFICATE OF SECONDARY EDUCATION. (KCSE C PLAIN)
BUKIRIMO PRIMARY SCHOOL	1999 TO 2007	KENYA CERTIFICATE OF PRIMARY EDUCATION. KCPE

## PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATION

DURATION (2021)	INSTITUTION	CISCO NETWORKING ACADEMY CERTIFICATIONS
2 MONTHS	KENYATTA UNIVERSITY	CISCO CERTIFIED NETWORK ASSOCIATE_CCNA I
2 MONTHS	KENYATTA UNIVERSITY	CISCO CERTIFIED NETWORK ASSOCIATE_CCNA II
2 MONTHS	KENYATTA UNIVERSITY	CISCO CERTIFIED NETWORK ASSOCIATE_CCNA III

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

POSITION HELD: ICT TRAINER AND TECHNICIAN

**EMPLOYER: SPRING INTERNATIONAL TRAINING COLLGE** 

FROM 15<sup>TH</sup>, February, 2024 up to date

#### **ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITES.**

- Undertaking training in areas of ICT in accordance with the syllabus.
- > Setting and marking examination/assignment.
- Supervising students' project and practical work.
- Installing and updating software in the computer lab.
- Ensuring WI-FI or internet connectivity is available.
- Setting up the new computer system.
- > Troubleshoot, configure and install software and hardware on computer.
- Sharing printer on Local Area Network.
- > Computer Support to staff and Students.
- > Designing e-fliers and posters then posting them in social media as required

POSITION HELD: ICT DIGITAL LITRACY PROGRAMME (ONE YEAR CONTRACT BASIS) EMPLOYER: MINISTRY OF EDUCATION, STATE DEPARTMENT OF BASIC EDUCATION. FROM 13<sup>RD</sup>, February, 2023 TO 12<sup>TH</sup> February, 2024.

#### **ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITES.**

- > Support e-learning and content development in line with curriculum designs.
- Provide class support and sensitization of primary school teachers in use of digital literacy devices.
- Carry out innovations to enable schools to improve on use of digital learning.
- Provide support in safe, secure and ethical use of technology in learning.
- Assist teachers in integrating ICT in delivery of teaching, learning and assessment.
- > Support school staff with development of school based ICT guidelines and procedures.
- > Provide first line support and maintenance of ICT devices and services in the schools.
- Perform any other related duty as may be assigned through the SCDE

POSITION HELD: SHOP ASSISTANT /ICT ASSISTANT.

EMPLOYER: HUMAN CAPITAL PROACTIVE CONSULTANTS LTD SECONDED TO EASTLEIGH MATRRSSES LTD (EASTMATT).

FROM 29<sup>TH</sup>, OCTOBER, 2020 TO 31<sup>ST</sup>, January, 2023.

#### **ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITES.**

- Performing basic administrative duties including price changes, sending and receiving emails.
- Making orders to suppliers.
- Assisting with inventory control.
- Resolving all ICT issues within the branch and liaising with ICT department in case of persistent issues that can be resolved at head quarter office.
- Assisting and coordinating with sales team head quarter office.

**POSITION HELD: ICT TRAINER AND TECHNICIAN** 

**EMPLOYER: THE SERENITY COLLEGE** 

FROM 8<sup>TH</sup>, January, 2018 TO 10<sup>TH</sup>, March, 2020

#### **ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITES.**

- Undertaking training in areas of ICT in accordance with the syllabus.
- Setting and marking examination/assignment.
- Supervising students' project and practical work.
- Installing and updating software in the computer lab.
- Ensuring WI-FI connectivity and computer systems are working
- > Setting up the new computer system.
- > Troubleshoot, configure and install software and hardware on computer.
- Sharing printer on Local Area Network.
- Computer repair and maintenance.

## **HOBBIES AND INTERESTS**

- Co-curricular activities.
- Watching football.
- Reading the bible.
- Reading newspapers.

## **REFEREES**

1. MINISTRY OF EDUCATION

STATE DEPARTMENT OF EARLY LEARNING & BASIC EDUCATION

EZRA ODONDI (SUB -COUNTY EDUCATION OFFICER)

TEL: 0770469320 / 0722985234

EMAIL: deobumula142abc@g.mail.com

2. HUMAN CAPITAL PROACTIVE CONSULTANTS LTD

TEL: +254 713 049 038/02023992570 EMAIL: <u>info@humancapital-pc.co.ke</u> WEBSITE: www.humancapital-pc.co.ke